Qasim Sarfraz

${\it syed.qasim.sarfraz@gmail.com} \\ {\it +4915204902253}$

Career Summary

Software Engineer with a passionate and a self driven personality with experience in software development and system engineering of cloud native softwares.

Computer Skills Languages & Software: Golang, Python, Ansible, Bash, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS and VSphere.

Operating Systems: Linux

Work Experience

DevOps/Backend Engineer at eSailors, Hamburg

Noc 2017- Present

- Part of a development team with keys roles including:
 - Planning and migrating on-premises platform to a cloud provider. (Kubernetes, Kubespray, Cilium and AWS)
 - Developing and maintaining product **micro-services** with cloud native approach. (Golang and Kubernetes)
 - Building reliable systems by running Kubernetes based platform in production on multiple cloud providers with centralized logging, monitoring and alerting solutions. (Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes and VSphere/AWS)

DevOps Engineer at INTECH Process Automation, Lahore Mar 2017- Oct 2017 - Responsible for deployment, maintenance, scalability and system engineering of advanced data and software solutions for IoT platform. (Ansible and DC/OS)

Design Engineer III at Xgrid, Islamabad

Oct 2014 - Feb 2017

- Senior member of PLUMgrid Cloud Solutions team with responsibilities including design and development of automated deployments, upgrades and maintenance of PLUMgrid Products. The key projects completed here include:
 - **Design and development** for PLUMgrid Docker based installation. (Puppet, Ansible, Bash and Docker)
 - Lead Developer for PLUMgrid and Red Hat OpenStack solution for automated installations and upgrades. (Puppet, Ansible, Bash and LXC)
 - **Developer** for PLUMgrid Life Cycle Manager for robust automated production grade deployments. (*Puppet and Bash*)

Site Experince at PLUMgrid HQ, California - 8 weeks training in PLUMgrid HQ, Santa Clara.

Jan-Mar 2016

Education

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering

2010-2014

University of Engineering and Technology, Lahore

Concentration: Computers

Achievements & Participation

Speaker at Honeypot Tech Talk with titile, Kubernetes - the eSailors way.

Contributor in open source communities e.g Kubespray, CoreDNS etc

PLUMgrid outstanding achievement award.